Top Menu [(425) 739-8100](tel:+1-425-739-8100)  

    * * Access
        
        * Academics
        
        * Services
        
        * Resources
    * * Access
        
        * Academics
        
        * Services
        
        * Resources
    
       Search

Main Menu [](https://www.lwtech.edu/)

    * * Degrees and Requirements
        
        * Degrees by Program
        
        * More Programs
        
        * Academic Resources
    * * Get Started
        
        * Student Services
        
        * Pay for College
        
        * Explore LWTech
    * * Campus Amenities
        
        * Student Support
        
        * Resources for Students
        
        * Student Life
    * * About Us
        
        * Departments
        
        * More LWTech
        
        * LWTech Information

×

Lake Washington Institute of Technology (LWTech) recently discovered that it was the victim of a data breach incident. With the privacy and security of our organization, its students, faculty, staff, and other community members who trust and rely on us as our priority, we took quick and thorough steps to secure our systems and activate additional cybersecurity protocols. Additional information about this incident can be a found on the 🔗[Data Security Incident Page.](https://www.lwtech.edu/news/data-security-incident/default.aspx "Link to external site")

[Home](https://www.lwtech.edu/) » [About LWTech](https://www.lwtech.edu/about/) » [Policies and Procedures](https://www.lwtech.edu/about/policies-and-procedures/) » Website Privacy Policy

Website Privacy Policy
======================

Thank you for visiting the Lake Washington Institute of Technology (LWTech) website and reviewing our privacy policy. This statement addresses collection, use, security of, and access to information that may be obtained through use of LWTech's website. This policy covers the following topics:

* Information Collected and How it is Used
* Personal Information and Choice
* Public Access to Information
* Nondisclosure of Certain Personal Information
* Security Disclaimer
* Contact Information

Information Collected & How It Is Used
--------------------------------------

Information Collected If You Only Browse The Website
----------------------------------------------------

If you do nothing during your visit to our website but browse, read pages, or download information, we will gather and store certain information about your visit. This information does not identify you personally. We automatically collect and store the following information about your visit:

* Internet protocol (IP) address and domain name used. The IP address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet service provider or directly to your computer. We use the IP address to direct Internet traffic to you. This address can be translated to determine the domain name of your service provider.
* Type of browser and operating system you used
* Date and time you visited this site
* Webpages or services you accessed at this site

The information we automatically collect or store is logged and used by LWTech only to improve the content and usefulness of our web services and to help us understand how people are using our website.

What We Collect If You Volunteer Information
--------------------------------------------

If during your visit to our website you participate in a survey, send an email, or perform some other transaction online, the following additional information will be collected:

* Email address, and contents of email, for those who communicate with us via email
* Information volunteered in response to a survey
* Information volunteered through an online form for any other purpose

The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats you send us.

We use your email to respond appropriately. This may be to respond to you, to address issues you identify, to further improve our website, or to forward the email to another agency for appropriate action. Survey information and information from other online forms is used for official college business only.

Personal Information and Choice
-------------------------------

You may choose whether to provide personal information online. Personal information is information about a person that is readily identifiable to that specific individual. Personal information includes such things as an individual's name, address, and phone number. A domain name or IP address is not considered personal information.

We collect no personal information about you unless you voluntarily provide it to us by sending us email, participating in a survey, or completing an online form. You may choose not to contact us by email, participate in a survey, or to provide any personal information using an online form. Your choice to not participate in these activities will not impair your ability to browse and read or download any information provided on the site. Alternatives such as mail, fax, or telephone are available if you so choose. Contact Lake Washington Institute of Technology by mail at 11605 132nd Ave NE, Kirkland, WA 98034 by phone at (425) 739-8100, or by fax at (425) 739-8110.

If personal information is requested on the website or volunteered by the user, state law and the federal Privacy Act of 1974 may protect it. However, this information is a public record once you provide it, and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by federal or state law.

If you believe that your personal information is being used for a purpose other than what was intended when submitted, you may contact Lake Washington Institute of Technology by mail at 11605 132nd Ave NE, Kirkland, WA 98034 by phone at (425) 739-8100, or by fax at (425) 739-8110.

The collection of personal information requested from or volunteered by children online or by email will be treated the same as information given by an adult, and may be subject to public access.

Public Access to Information
----------------------------

In the State of Washington, laws exist to ensure that government is open and that the public has a right to access appropriate records and information possessed by state government. At the same time, there are exceptions to the public's right to access public records that serve various needs including the privacy of individuals. Exceptions are provided by both state and federal laws.

All of the information collected at this site becomes public records that may be subject to inspection and copying by members of the public, unless an exemption in law exists. Statue RCW 42.17.260(1) states that:

Each agency, in accordance with published rules, shall make available for public inspection and copying all public records, unless the record falls within the specific exemptions of subsection (6) of this section \[RCW 42.17.260(6)\], RCW 42.17.310, 42.17.315, or other statute which exempts or prohibits disclosure of specific information or records. To the extent required to prevent an unreasonable invasion of personal privacy interests protected by RCW 42.17.310 and 42.17.315, an agency shall delete identifying details in a manner consistent with RCW 42.17.310 and 42.17.315 when it makes available or publishes any public record; however, in each case, the justification for the deletion shall be explained fully in writing.

In the event of a conflict between this Privacy Notice and the Public Records Act or other law governing the agency's disclosure of records, the Public Records Act or other applicable law will control.

The complete [Revised Code of Washington](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/ "Link to an external site") (RCW) is available.

Nondisclosure of Certain Personal Information
---------------------------------------------

You may be required to provide certain personal information when you use the web-enabled applications that are described below.

Credit Card Payment
-------------------

Lake Washington Institute of Technology may require you to provide certain personal information in order to pay tuition and fees over the web. The information is required in order to verify your identify and to verify your credit card number and expiration date. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to apply tuition and fee payment over the web and you will have to pay your tuition and fees in person.

Student Information
-------------------

Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Directory information may include student's name, address, telephone number, date and place of birth, major fields of study, participation in officially recognized activities and sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received, the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended by the student, and other similar information.

Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order, or legal report. Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested.

* Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA) Section 438, Public Law 90 247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571 574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
* RCW 42.17.310 (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients; (ss) Credit card numbers, debit card numbers, electronic check numbers, card expiration dates, or bank or other financial account numbers supplied to an agency for the purpose of electronic transfer of funds, except when disclosure is expressly required by law.

Academic Advisement Report
--------------------------

Lake Washington Institute of Technology may require you to provide certain personal information in order to perform a academic advisement report of your records over the web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to display a academic advisement report of your records over the web, and you will have to request a academic advisement report in person at the Enrollment Services Office.

Financial Aid Inquiry
---------------------

Lake Washington Institute of Technology may require you to provide certain personal information in order to obtain your financial aid status over the web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to give you your financial aid status over the web, and you will have to obtain this information in person at the Financial Aid Office.

Hope and Lifetime Learning Tax Credit
-------------------------------------

Lake Washington Institute of Technology may require you to provide certain personal information in order to allow you to view and copy course enrollment and payment information. The information is required in order to provide you with the tax information needed for compliance with the Internal Revenue Service reporting requirements for the Hope and Lifetime Leaning tax credits. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it, we will be unable to display your enrollment and payment information and you will have to obtain a copy of your enrollment and payment records in person at the Cashier in the Enrollment Services Office.

Registration
------------

Lake Washington Institute of Technology may require you to provide certain personal information in order to register for classes over the web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it you will be unable to register for classes over the web, and you will have to register for classes in person.

Registration Appointment
------------------------

Lake Washington Institute of Technology may require you to provide certain personal information in order to obtain your registration appointment information over the web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to display your registration appointment information over the web, and you will have to obtain your registration appointment information address in person at the Enrollment Services Office.

Student Address Change
----------------------

Lake Washington Institute of Technology may require you to provide certain personal information in order to change your address over the web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to change your address over the web, and you will have to change your address in person at the Enrollment Services Office.

Student Schedule
----------------

Lake Washington Institute of Technology may require you to provide certain personal information in order to view your quarterly schedule. The information is required in order to verify you identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to display your quarterly schedule over the web, and you will have to obtain a copy of your quarterly schedule in person at the Enrollment Services Office.

Unofficial Transcript
---------------------

Lake Washington Institute of Technology may require you to provide certain personal information in order to view your unofficial transcript over the web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to display your unofficial transcript over the web, and you will have to view your unofficial transcript in person at Enrollment Services.

Review and Correction of Personally Identifiable Information
------------------------------------------------------------

You can review any personally identifiable information Lake Washington Institute of Technology collects about you by using the information in the Contact Information section at the end of this notice. You may recommend changes to your personally identifiable information you believe to be inaccurate by submitting a written request that credibly shows the inaccuracy. We will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections (RCW 43.105.310).

Security
--------

Lake Washington Institute of Technology, as developer and manager of [www.lwtech.edu](https://www.lwtech.edu/), has taken several steps to safeguard the integrity of its data and prevent unauthorized access to information maintained by Lake Washington Institute of Technology.

These measures are designed and intended to prevent corruption of data, block unknown or unauthorized access to our systems and information, and to provide reasonable protection of private information in our possession.

This information should not be construed in any way as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided via Lake Washington Institute of Technology websites.

Disclaimer
----------

The Lake Washington Institute of Technology website has many links to other websites. These include links to websites operated by other government agencies, nonprofit organizations, and private businesses. When you link to another site, you are no longer on the Lake Washington Institute of Technology website and this privacy notice will not apply. When you link to another website, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site.

Reference in this website to any specific commercial products, processes or services, or the use of any trade, firm, or corporation name is for the information and convenience of the public, and does not constitute endorsement, recommendation, or favoring by the State of Washington, Lake Washington Institute of Technology, its officers, employees, or agents.

Neither the State of Washington, nor any agency, officer, or employee of the State of Washington warrants the accuracy, reliability, or timeliness of any information published by this system, nor endorses any content, viewpoints, products, or services linked from this system, and shall not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance on the accuracy, reliability, or timeliness of such information. Portions of such information may be incorrect or not current. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained from this system does so at their own risk.

Contact Information
-------------------

You may contact Lake Washington Institute of Technology as follows:

To review your personal information, or request correction of your personal information:

Enrollment Services  
Lake Washington Institute of Technology  
11605 132nd Ave NE  
Kirkland, WA 98034  
(425) 739-8100 main  
(425) 739-8110 fax

To offer comments about Lake Washington Institute of Technology's website or about the information presented in this privacy notice:

Information Technology Services  
Lake Washington Institute of Technology  
11605 132nd Ave NE  
Kirkland, WA 98034  
(425) 739-8603 main  
(425) 739-8277 fax

###### [Policies and Procedures](https://www.lwtech.edu/about/policies-and-procedures/)

Contact Info

Kirkland Campus  

  [Kirkland Campus  
11605 132nd Avenue NE  
Kirkland, WA 98034](https://www.lwtech.edu/about/directions/)

 Business Hours  
Mon-Fri, 7:30 a.m. to 4:30 p.m.

 Campus Hours  
Mon-Thurs, 6 a.m. to 10 p.m.  
Friday, Closed to the public  
Sat-Sun, Closed  

Accessibility

Lake Washington Institute of Technology (LWTech) is committed to providing access to information for all, therefore we are taking the following measures to ensure accessibility of the college’s public facing website (LWTech.edu), and third-party platforms utilized by students, staff, and community members.

The college is currently conducting an audit to determine the extent to which its website and third-party platforms are compliant.

[Learn more about accessibility and the current audit](https://www.lwtech.edu/about/policies-and-procedures/accessible-technology/).

Useful Links

Translate

_This website is best viewed in [Chrome](https://www.google.com/chrome/ "Link to external site"), [Edge](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/edge "Link to external site"), or [Firefox](https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/new/ "Link to external site")_

Last Updated:   | 2023 Copyright © Lake Washington Institute of Technology

Please enable JavaScript to view this page.

Please enable JavaScript to view this page.
